We had twenty years to prepare. So did they.
Independence Day: Resurgence is a action, adventure, science
fiction film directed by Roland Emmerich.
We always knew they were coming back.
Using recovered alien technology, the nations of Earth have
collaborated on an immense defense program to protect the planet.
But nothing can prepare us for the aliens’ advanced and unprecedented force.
Only the ingenuity of a few brave men and women can bring
our world back from the brink of extinction.
Jake Morrison, played by Liam Hemsworth.
David Levinson, played by Jeff Goldblum.
Dylan Hiller, played by Jessie T. Usher.
President Whitmore, played by Bill Pullman.
Patricia Whitmore, played by Maika Monroe.
Charlie Miller, played by Travis Tope.
Independence Day: Resurgence is a 2016 American science fiction action film co-written, directed, and co-produced by Roland
Emmerich and co-written and co-produced by Dean Devlin, serving as a standalone sequel to Independence Day (1996).
It stars an ensemble cast that consists of Liam Hemsworth, Jeff
Goldblum, Bill Pullman, Maika Monroe, Jessie T.
Usher, Travis Tope, William Fichtner, Charlotte Gainsbourg, and Judd Hirsch.
The film takes place twenty years after the events of the first film, during which the United Nations has
collaborated to form the Earth Space Defense, an international military defense and research organization.
Through reverse engineering, the world has fused the power of alien technology
with humanity's and laid the groundwork to resist a second invasion.
Plans for a sequel to Independence Day began as early as 2001, with 20th
Century Fox eventually green-lighting the project in 2014.
Principal photography began in April 2015 at locations primarily in New Mexico but also in
the Bonneville Salt Flats of Utah, which were featured in the original.
This was one of Robert Loggia's final projects before he died, and the film is
dedicated in memory of him and he is commemorated during its closing credits.
Independence Day: Resurgence was released by 20th Century Fox in the United States on June 24,
2016, twenty years after the release of Independence Day, in 2D, 3D, and IMAX 3D.
It received largely negative reviews from critics and audiences who felt the film lacked the hype of the original and was a
financial disappointment, grossing $389.7 million worldwide at the box office against its $165 million budget.
Following the film's release, director Emmerich openly expressed his dissatisfaction with the completed film, as he
regretted making it without Will Smith's involvement (Smith was one of the central protagonists in the first film).
The tone is thought_provoking.